Ahmy Yulrizka

Senior Software Engineer



ADDRESS

NATIONALITY

Musicallaan 155, Utrecht, 3543EC,

The Netherlands

Indonesian

EMAIL LINKS yulrizka@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/yulrizka, github.com/yulrizka, labs.yulrizka.com

Profile

I have more than 11 years of experience in software development. I involved in designing, architect, and implementing high throughput systems serving traffic for one of the top popular sites in the Netherlands.

As part of a team, my potential contributions would be to collaborate with the team and business to rapidly iterate on a design and implementation of new functionalities as well as maintaining, improving, and scaling the current system.

Main skill sets:

Programming Languages: Golang, ruby, python, java **Databases**: MySQL, Cassandra, Clickhouse, Redis

Queues: Kafka, ActiveMQ, RabbitMQ

Deployments: Hashistack (Nomad, Terraform, Consul), Openstack, Salt, Puppet

Employment History

Aug 2015 - Present

AMSTERDAM, THE NETHERLANDS

Lead Software Engineer

eBay Classified Group/Marktplaats

Initially, I started working as a software developer with a role to design and implement multiple micro-services to support high-throughput systems. Currently, I am leading the platform sub-team which focuses on closing gaps between developers and operations with automation.

Key technologies: Go, MySQL, Clickhouse, Elasticsearch, HashiStack (consul, nomad), Kafka, Redis

Responsibilities:

- · Leading migration from running on bare metal to a scheduled environment in the cloud.
- · Leading migration from legacy search engine to Elasticsearch.
- · Design and implement an asynchronous image processing pipeline.
- · Involved in designing a high throughput analytic engine.
- · Represent my team in the Architect Group.

Jun 2012 — Jul 2015

ROTTERDAM, THE NETHERLANDS

Software Engineer

Sense Observation Systems

Sense OS is a start-up that focuses on providing IOT platform with an intelligent agent that empowers developers to build smart applications. My main role was to expand and scale the back-end system

Key technologies: Go, PHP, Ruby & Rails, Cassandra, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS (EC2, Route53, S3), Openstack, Kafka, Redis, ELK Stack, Chef, Android (java), iOS (Swift & Objective-C). Frontend (JS, Angular, CSS, Haml, Compass, Sass)

Responsibilities:

- Scale the platform by designing and implementing microservices
- Evaluate, implement and maintain message queuing architecture that enables real-time processing
- Design and implement real time monitoring allowing insight and immediate action upon system disruption.
- Deploy automation allowing easy and fast deployment and the ability to switch cloud providers which provides cost-effective, high available system.
- Take part in mobile development both Android and iOS.
- · Fronted development for dashboard application.

Jan 2009 — Jan 2012 BANDUNG, INDONESIA

Chief Technology Officer

PT Starqle Indonesia

Starqle is a small startup that mainly develops software for companies and government institutions.

Key technologies: Ruby (and rails, sinatra), Java (hibernate, JBoss Seam), PHP, MySQL, Git, SVN

Responsibilities:

- · Responsible for determining framework and architecture used for Development.
- · Lead a team as project managers on several projects.
- · Establish policy and development workflow with test-driven development.
- Identify and explore new technology and project management that would be suitable for projects.

Mar 2008 - Jan 2009

BANDUNG, INDONESIA

Software Developer

PT. Zamrud Khatulistiwa Technology

I started my career as a junior software developer at Zamrud Khatilistiwa Technology. This company develops a custom solution for the private sector in which I involved mainly as a programmer.

Responsibilities:

- Lead developer crayonpedia.org. Customizing mediawiki engines to create an encyclopedia that follows the national school curriculum.
- · As a developer of financial systems for the local state government.
- · As a developer of administration support systems used by one of the national agencies.
- Establish policies and software version control systems to enable collaborative development.

Key technologies: Javascript (Extjs), PHP, Java (Spring, DWR, Hibernate), Mysql, Subversion

Education

Master of Information System

Major: Information Systems

- · Software Engineering, Information Engineering, Enterprise Process & Modeling.
- Strategic Information Planning, Strategy & Policy of Information System.
- · Management of Information System, Information System Governance.
- · Risk Management of Information System, Project & Change Management

2004 - 2008

BANDUNG

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Bachelor of Informatics

Major: Information System

- · Algorithm & Data Structure, Algorithmic Strategies, Internet Programming
- · Object Oriented Programming, Object Oriented Analysis & Design
- · Database System, Operating System, System Programming
- · Software Engineering, Software Project Management
- · Wireless Mobile Computing

Licenses & Certificates

Mar 2017 - Present

DATASTAX

DataStax Certified Professional on DataStax Enterprise (Cassandra, Spark, DSE Search, DSE Graph)

Credential ID: 952c0c8f-5047-4eaa-a9c6-033aca4ea8c8

https://academy.datastax.com/

Dec 2015 - Present

COURSERA

Machine Learning

Credential ID: HXSL3KT2GRP8

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/HXSL3KT2GRP8

Nov 2013 — Nov 2015 AMAZON WEB SERVICE

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Level

Credential ID: AWS-ASA-1810

http://aws.amazon.com/certification/

Honors & Awards

Feb 2015

BANDUNG OPEN DATA

1st place Bandung Open Data Summit & Challenge "BOSCHA 2015"

Aug 2014

CMI EN CREATING010

1st place Data of the Crowds Hackathon

CMI en Creating010 van Hogeschool Rotterdam, Zeewaardig en Gemeente Rotterdam

2012 4th Best on Indosat Wireless Innovation Contest category android
2007 2nd Best on Codefest Asia 2007
CODE ASIA

Indonesian

Dutch

English